We are all familiar with one or another form of near field communication enabled devices.
What's.
Near field communication and applications.
As I said before, near field communication is a technology to transfer information between devices
in proximity using RF signals.
NFC technology offers a wide range of features, from keyless access to smart tags for medical applications,
the option to implement and embed it into credit cards, smartphones and other wearable devices makes
NFC technology one of the most convenient ones.
So let's have a look at the different NFC applications.
First of all, smart cards payment using NFC integrated smart cards offer easier payment compared to
the conventional multiple step payment process.
Top payment services like Visa and Smart Card are offering NFC embedded smart cards to customers.
NFC integrated smart cards can be used for fast payment at grocery shops, parking tickets, adding
shopping points, reading coupons with just a single tap of the card.
All the major banks around the globe offer smart cards with integrated NFC chips.
Second, we have e-wallet, which means payment using a smartphone.
Cashless payment system using mobile devices became popular at the beginning of this decade, and more
services are offering cashless payment for customers convenience using smartphone applications.
Payment can be made using a simple tap or waving the card within proximity.
Service providers can integrate a payment option into smartphones using an NFC tag embedded inside the
device.
Apple pay, Google Wallet, Android Pay, and Samsung Pay are the most popular smartphone payment systems.
Data transfer using the smart device is possible using NFC technology like Android Beam.
Two users can share documents, photos, resumes, and business cards by just waving their smartphones.
Then we have smart ticketing.
Integrated smart chips can be used to replace traditional ticketing system with smart tickets for airlines,
train and bus tickets, etc. NFC tags can be used for smart posters, movie tickets, tickets to concerts,
advertisements, flyers, and information links.
Customers will be able to access a reserved area or activate tickets by just tapping NFC tags located
at the assigned location.
More information, for example, can be found by just scanning the smart tag.
Then we have medicine and health care for example.
So NFC integrated systems can be used in medicine and health care activities.
NFC offers greater accuracy and convenience in prescribing medicine, easier check in payments, checking
the status of patients and tracking records by embedding NFC tags to patient charts.
NFC integrated devices can be easily paired and configured.
Medical professionals can easily check schedules and access medical devices and equipment.
The future of NFC in health care is very promising, and many companies have already started investing.
Diagnostic tests are under development for monitoring medical conditions like temperature variations.
Blood glucose level fluctuation, etc., etc..
Fifth, we have keyless access.
Keyless access is one of the familiar applications of near-field communication today.
NFC is convenient and easy to implement feature make it a popular choice.
NFC and RFID tags can be used for access to doors and restricted area with a node to detect feature.
It can be used to replace access keys and identification badges, and for easier access to cars and
other vehicles.
Then we have manufacturing.
Smart tags are used in motor manufacturing industries to identify each product from its different processing
stages within the company packaging, transportation, and tracking of products during shipment.
Unique identification numbers allow manufacturers to efficiently manage products in case of return during
the warranty period for replacement, service, and maintenance.
Then we have logistics and shipping.
NFC and RFID tags can be conveniently used in the logistics and shipping industry.
Tracking and scanning of goods using smart tags makes the system smart, errorless, and efficient.
Eighth, we have smart inventory management.
For example, retail shops and large scale supermarkets can make use of smart RFID tags for better management
of inventories in their system.
Smart inventory management software can give a real time update on products details for customers and
items in their inventory stock, and it could trigger automatic orders if a particular item has a low
quantity.
Vendors will get an update on items in high demand and better service can be provided.
Ninth, we have the theft control.
Another attractive use of RFID tags is theft control.
Valuable things can be protected using smart tags.
Objects embedded with smart tags will trigger if they pass by RFID.
Proximity.
The active area where the RFID transmitter is installed.
Finally, we have NFC information tags similar to QR code scanning using a smartphone camera.
Users can access information with NFC tags.
If someone wants to access information about product or service, for example, it can be accessed by
just tapping their phone on the NFC Smart Tag.